Juan Casse Los Angeles, CA (310) 913-7306 jcasse@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/juan-casse gitlab.com/jcasse

# Software Engineer

A software developer at heart, I am passionate about writing extensible and maintainable code. With an academic background in machine learning and artificial intelligence, my ideal job consists of developing software for AI applications. Fortunate to have had a diverse experience in industry: architected, designed and implemented an automated testing and reporting framework for mobile applications, implemented a fuzzy inference engine as a Python package, developed a web service for an AI engine, conducted data science work, and more.

#### **Technical Tools**

Languages: Python (expert) · C/C++ (proficient) · Java · Lisp · Objective-C · R · Bash · SQL · Matlab · ŁTŁX

Software: Emacs · Vim · Android Studio · Xcode · R Studio · Git · Gerrit · Jira · Linux · MacOS · Docker

# Experience in Industry

# Beyond Limits, Inc.

Leader in industrial-grade artificial intelligence (AI) solutions

Glendale, CA

Al Software Engineer

October 2017 - present

• Develop software for artificial intelligence applications.

# InAuth, Inc., an American Express company

Leader in mobile-first authentication and fraud prevention

Santa Monica, CA July 2016 - October 2017

SDET

• Developed cross-platform, test automation framework for the company's mobile SDK products. It runs on Linux and OS X, operates on Android and iOS devices, is extensible and provides end-to-end automation, writing

# Children's Hospital Los Angeles

Award-winning, non-profit, research hospital providing life-saving care to children

Los Angeles, CA

Data Scientist

December 2014 - July 2016

• Developed algorithm to diagnose patients. It transformed each patient's heterogeneous, messy and irregularly sampled longitudinal data from electronic health records into a fixed-length feature vector, relative to every other patient in the ICU. The interrelation between variables and their timing information was modeled in a principled way as a marked point process. The number of clusters was automatically selected by the algorithm.

results to an MS Excel spreadsheet in the cloud. It reduces a month of work of three QA testers to two hours.

• Implemented packages in R and Python for data cleaning and analysis.

## Google, Inc.

Multinational, technology company specializing in Internet-related services and products

Mountain View, CA

Software Engineering Intern

June 2013 - September 2013

- Contributed to open source software, Flexible I/O Tester (fio).
- Developed Linux utility in C to test data integrity and retention of storage devices.

# Experience in Academia

# **University of California Riverside**

Public research university, part of the University of California system

Riverside, CA

**Graduate Student Researcher** 

June 2012 - September 2014

Implemented clustering algorithms (20K lines of C++ code) in support of my research.

Associate Instructor

April 2012 - June 2012

• Taught CS 14 Introduction to Data Structures and Algorithms.

Teaching Assistant

September 2009 - June 2013

Held laboratory sessions, graded assignments, and held office hours for various CS courses.

#### Harvey Mudd College

Top-ranked college of science, engineering and mathematics Instructor Claremont, CA

• Taught CS 151 Artificial Intelligence.

January 2011 – May 2011

Juan Casse page 2 of 2

#### **Previous Professional Experience**

### Lifescan, a Johnson & Johnson company

Manufacturer of blood glucose monitoring systems for home and hospital use

Cabo Rojo, PR

Staff Engineer

January 2002 - December 2004

- Introduced new-technology automation to our manufacturing process.
- Worked closely with machine builders through conceptual design, reviews and validation.

# Senior Manufacturing Engineer

August 1997 – January 2002

- Improved process yield from 75% to 85% through 6-sigma projects.
- Integrated vision inspection systems on all manufacturing lines to ensure correct labeling.

#### **Baxter Biotech Group Fenwal Division**

Medical device manufacturer of products used in the delivery of fluids/drugs and hemodialysis San German, PR

Project Engineer - Factory Automation September 1993 - September 1997

- Designed and built automated manufacturing equipment for various facilities worldwide.
- Supervised personnel and coordinated work in automation group's machine shop.
- Integrated radiation-based sterilization process.

# Other Technical Experience

Web IDE (2018) Web-based IDE, deployed in Docker. Python, Flask, Apache Http Server, Ace, GoldenLayout

Experimenter (2015) Multi-threaded, GUI-based workflow tool. C++, wxWidgets

Automatic Grader (2012) Coding assignment grading and reporting system. Bash, C++

Interactive 3D Visualization (2011) GUI for viewing a clustering of cubed data. C++, OpenGL

Convoy Routing (2007) Genetic algorithm for optimal scheduling of convoys on shared roads. C++, Java

# Education

# Ph.D. in Computer Science (GPA 3.9) University of California, Riverside

December 2014

Dissertation: Automatic Co-clustering for Social Network and Medical Data

# M.S. in Computer Science (GPA 3.9) California State University, Long Beach

May 2008

Thesis: Convoy Routing and scheduling using Augmented Beam Search, RSBS

#### B.S. in Electrical Engineering (GPA 2.5) Marguette University, Milwaukee

August 1992

Senior Project: Robotic arm to demonstrate cell manufacturing to future classes

#### **Publications**

Islam, Kazi T., Shelton, Christian R., Casse, Juan I. and Wetzel, Randall (2017). **Marked Point Process for Severity of Illness Assessment**. Proceedings of Machine Learning for Healthcare 2017. JMLR W&C Track Volume 68.

Casse, Juan Ignacio (2014). Automatic Co-clustering for Social Network and Medical Data. Ph.D. Dissertation, University of California Riverside, Riverside, CA.

Casse, J., Shelton, C., Hanneman, R. (2013). A new criterion function for exploratory blockmodeling for structural and regular equivalence. Social Networks, 35(1), 32–50.

Casse, J.I., Shelton, C.R., and Hanneman R.A. (2011). Alternating Optimization Algorithm for Block-modeling Two-way Two-mode Data with Unknown Number of Clusters. Regular Session on Social Networks for the 2011 ASA.

Goldstein, D., Shehab, T., Casse, J., and Lin, H. (2010). **On the formulation and solution of the convoy routing problem**. Transportation Research Part E: Logistics and Transportation Review, 46(4), 520.

Casse, J.I. (2008). Convoy Routing and Scheduling using Augmented Beam Search RSBS. Master's thesis, California State University, Long Beach, CA.